<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="10"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[PROJECT PROPOSAL BRIEFING NOTE
                         PREPARED FOR


























         Integrated Platform




         for the Simulation of




         Offshore Aquaculture Structures
      +61 3 6226 2429                                              ali.tolooiyan@utas.edu.au







































                                             ali.tolooiyan@utas.edu.au
                                                    +61 3 6226 2429
                                                             1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PROJECT


                                                          SUMMARY




                                                          For every offshore aquaculture project, the complex
                                                          loading  conditions,  nonlinear  material  behaviour,
                                                          and  extensive  multi-physical  interfaces  between
                                                          the  sea  flow,  seabed  soil,  waves,  and  structural
                                                          components  such  as  pens,  anchors  and  mooring
                                                          system, necessitates the need to analyse and select
                                                          the best combination of the structural components,
                                                          through either traditional full-scale trial testing or
                                                          numerical  analysis.  Since  full-scale  trial  testing  is
                                                          usually  associated  with  unreasonable  cost,  time,
                                                          and risk, numerical simulation is preferred to full-
                                                          scale trial testing.

                                                          Although several commercial numerical simulation
                                                          packages  have  been  developed,  there  remains  a
                                                          serious lack of integrated multi-physical numerical
                                                          modelling  packages  for  the  comprehensive
                                                          simulation  of  offshore  aquaculture  structures.
                                                          Currently,  all  existing  packages  fail  in  the
                                                          simultaneous simulation of the three essential multi-
                                                          physical  interfaces  (fluid-soil,  fluid-structure,  and
                                                          soil-structure). This means several packages should
                                                          be  used  concurrently  to  achieve  the  simulation
                                                          objectives.  This  concurrent  application  requires
                                                          the  results  from  one  package  to  be  exported  to
                                                          another package, back-and-forth and iteratively to
                                                          take the neglected interfaces into account. Such a
                                                          complex sequential pattern makes the analysis less
                                                          precise,  more  expensive,  more  time-consuming,
                                                          less realistic, or even impossible.


                                                          Aimed  to  avoid  this  expensive,  unreliable  and
                                                          time-consuming pattern, the integrated simulation
                                                          platform offered in this project combines existing
                                                          modelling methods, tools, knowledge and expertise
                                                          in one single platform which can be used directly by
                                                          the relevant aquaculture industry for the simulation
                                                          and analysis of offshore aquaculture and modular
                                                          multi-use  platform  systems,  and  lead  to  the
                                                          selection of the most suitable design, structural set-
                                                          up, installation method, and construction material.





                                                             2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[WHAT IS LACKING ?





          In recent times, the growing demand for high-quality protein sources, coupled with technological
          advancements has facilitated a range of developments in offshore sea-cage aquaculture. From
          a structural engineering point of view, many of these advances have led to durable and cost-
          effective materials for the construction of fish pens, reliable anchoring and mooring systems,
          cost-effective and practical pen designs, and various computer systems for the monitoring of
          structural components. However, as field conditions such as wave height and energy, water
          depth  and  geotechnical  properties  of  the  seabed  affect  the  performance  of  every  offshore
          aquaculture system, the engineering design of the system is completely dependent on field
          conditions. This means there is no such thing as the best pen design, most suitable construction
          material,  or  most  cost-effective  and  reliable  anchoring  and  mooring  system,  as  a  generic
          engineering solution to all the challenges associated with field conditions.


          In fact, for every offshore aquaculture project, subject to the field conditions, one needs to
          analyse, validate, verify and ultimately choose the best combination of the structural components
          for this particular project through either traditional full-scale trial testing or novel numerical
          analysis. Since full-scale trial testing is usually associated with unreasonable cost, time, and risk,
          numerical simulation is preferred to full-scale trial testing. However, no commercial numerical
          analysis  package  has  yet  been  developed  for  the  comprehensive  simulation  of  offshore
          aquaculture structures.










































                                                             3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[WHAT THIS PROJECT OFFERS








         The  proposed  research  project  does  not  aim  to  develop  a  new  analysis  software  package
         which may impose extra time and cost to the industry by reinventing the wheel. Instead, the
         integrated simulation platform offered in this project combines existing modelling methods,
         tools,  knowledge  and  expertise  in  one  single  package,  both  iteratively  and  in  parallel.  This
         comprehensive modelling platform facilitates the realistic simulation of individual structural
         components of an offshore aquaculture system, as well as their interactions and interfaces,
         while taking into account the effects of field conditions in both low- and high-energy areas. By
         using this platform, local and international industry stakeholders can explore and analyse a
         range of what-if scenarios and answer essential project-based questions (please see below).


         Through  the  realistic  simulation  of  potential  scenarios,  stakeholders  can  choose  the  most
         suitable design, installation method, and construction material, which leads to gain in efficiency,
         reliability and safety of a commercial-ready design for offshore aquaculture pens as well as
         other structures such as floating breakwaters and modular multi-use platform systems, and
         their interaction with the existing or future pens, in both low or high-energy environments.


                                                                   -  How  does  the  sea  hydrodynamics  affect
                                                                   the integrity of the structure?


                                                                   -  Considering  the  characterisation  of  the
                                                                   seabed,  what  are  the  most  cost-effective
                                                                   and  reliable  anchoring  and  mooring
                                                                   systems?


                                                                   -  What  are  the  required  collapse  loads  in
                                                                   different  field  conditions,  should  the  pen
                                                                   construction material change?


                                                                   - Considering the energy intensity, what is
                                                                   the most reliable and optimum cage design?


                                                                   -  Between  the  strengthening  of  the  cage/
                                                                   mooring systems, and lessening the wave
                                                                   energy through the construction of a floating
                                                                   breakwater,  what  is  the  most  economical
                                                                   solution for farming in high-energy areas?








                                                             4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[NUMERICAL MODELLING








                MULTI-PHYSICS
                                          State-of-the-art  numerical  modelling  is  one  of  the  two  engines
                                          behind  this  project.  Driven  by  this  particular  engine,  advanced
                      SIMULATION
                                          numerical methods are employed when each method requires

                                          unique numerical time-stepping, algorithms, meshing techniques,
                                          procedures to investigate the behaviour of the considered system.


                                          Some of the Numerical Methods in this Platform:



                                          I.      Finite Element Method (FEM):
                                          II.     Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD):
                                          III.    Coupled Eulerian-Lagrangian (CEL):

                                          IV.     Smoothed-Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH):

































          Physical Elements                                         Multi-Physical Interfaces

          A.   Flow                                                 a.   Fluid-Soil Interaction
          B.   Geotechnical                                         b.   Fluid-Structure Interaction eotechnical
          C.   Wave                                                 c.    Soil-Structure Interaction
          D.   Structural Components









                                                             5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[UNIVERSITIES



         INVOLVED





















         Several research-active universities will be involved in the project, including:

         •  University of Tasmania (UTAS) - Australia

         •  The University of Western Australia (UWA) - Australia

         •  Griffith University - Australia

         •  Universidad Austral de Chile (UACh) - Chile



                                                             6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[PHYSICAL MODELLING








                                                                                                                  UTAS AMC Model Test Basin

























                                                                                                                  UWA  Centrifuge Facility



















          State-of-the-art  physical  modelling  is  the  second  driving  force  behind  this  project.  Not  all
          questions  regarding  the  design  and  optimisation  of  offshore  structures  can  be  answered
          through numerical modelling. This is when the importance of realistic physical modelling kicks
          in. Physical modelling is essential for the calibration of numerical model inputs as well as the
          validation and verification of the results determined from the numerical simulation.


          The UTAS AMC model test basin is equipped with specialised instrumentation including a wave-
          maker, a wind generator and a state-of-the-art quality digital video motion capture system,
          to facilitate the physical study of the behaviour of downscaled structural components under
          realistic field loading conditions.


          The geotechnical centrifuge facility at UWA is necessary for understanding the behaviour of the
          anchors as well as the geotechnical behaviour of the seabed. The other advantage of centrifuge
          modelling in this project is time-scaling whereby some geotechnical reactions that take decades
          to produce in the field can be scaled down to and investigated in several days.



                                                             7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[VALIDATION AND VERIFICATION (V&V)





         The  V&V  methodology  implemented  in  this  platform  is  offered  to  make  numerical  model
         predictions  with  high  confidence.  Through  comparing  the  numerical  results  versus  those
         captured from either physical testing or provided by industry partners, V&V allows for a reduction
         in the cost, time, and risk associated with future full-scale testing or final construction.





         DESIGN AND OPTIMISATION (D&O)





         The numerical modelling, physical modelling and V&V features designed and integrated into
         this platform work both collaboratively and iteratively, to offer the optimum and reliable design.
         This process plays an important role to avoid any unnecessary costs or time-related delay to the
         traditionally used trial and error methods.

















































                                                             8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Academic Personnel






                                       Dr Ali Tolooiyan                            UTAS



                                 Dr Gholamreza Kefayati                            UTAS



                                     Prof Andrew Chan                              UTAS


                                   Dr Nagi Abdussamie                              UTAS


                                 Prof Christophe Gaudin                            UWA



                                  Dr Hassan Karampour                         Griffith Uni.



                                    Dr Gonzalo Tampier                            UACh




                                   Dr Cristian Cifuentes                          UACh



























                                                             9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Prepared by




                                                      Dr Ali Tolooiyan


                            School of Engineering, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Australia



                                                          Feb. 2020
































                 +61 3 6226 2429                                              ali.tolooiyan@utas.edu.au








                                                             10]]></page></pages></Search>